<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0">
  <channel>
    <title>Jehan Alvani</title>
    <description>Follow &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/jalvani&quot;&gt;@jalvani on Micro.blog&lt;/a&gt;.</description>
    <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/</link>
    <pubDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 18:11:15 -0700</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Nov 2018 18:11:15 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/e172b9bd0a.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/2438c05697.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 31 Oct 2018 19:17:57 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/31/021757.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/11/01/021757.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Couldn’t we have let Hill wear his Dick Mountain jersey for the rest of his season? Seems like the right way to respect its greatness. ⚾️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 27 Oct 2018 18:58:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/27/couldnt-we-have.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/28/couldnt-we-have.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I sank an hour before bed playing &lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/donut-county/id1292099839?mt=8&quot;&gt;Donut County&lt;/a&gt;. If you were a fan of Katamari Damacy, this short iOS gem will be right up your alley.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 26 Oct 2018 09:39:58 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/26/i-sank-an.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/26/i-sank-an.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Me, complaining that our toaster sometimes is a jerk: It’s 2018, it’s nearly 2019! It’s not hard to build electronics that compensate for a warm heating element and decrease the cook time accordingly    &lt;br /&gt;
Lindsay: Oh my god, it’s a toaster let’s get mad about it.     &lt;br /&gt;
Me: I mean, I listened to a podcast where toasters were reviewed…       &lt;br /&gt;
Lindsay: 😶 Are you ok? Do you need friends?      &lt;br /&gt;
Me: Well, I…        &lt;br /&gt;
Lindsay: I mean, I know you’re a nerd but sometimes you really amaze me with how much of a nerd you really are.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 20 Oct 2018 09:26:01 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/20/me-complaining-that.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/20/me-complaining-that.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been fighting with In-Air WiFi all day, and as frustrating as it is it’s also still incredible.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Oct 2018 15:42:04 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/11/ive-been-fighting.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/11/ive-been-fighting.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Dr. Zeynep Tufekci on the Fundamentally Broken Incentive Structure in Social Media Business Models</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/10/03/opinion/midterms-facebook-foreign-meddling.html&quot;&gt;Russian Meddling Is a Symptom, Not the Disease&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Facebook, Twitter and YouTube have business models that thrive on the outrageous, the incendiary and the eye-catching, because such content generates “engagement” and captures our attention, which the platforms then sell to advertisers, paired with extensive data on users that allow advertisers (and propagandists) to “microtarget” us at an individual level.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The way social media incentivized divisive, eye-catching (and often factually incomplete if not entirely wrong) posts is a huge problem we don’t talk about or have any idea how to fix. And don’t look to Google and Facebook to fix this problem: to them, this problem is engagement, and makes their platforms more valuable.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 09:50:02 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/05/dr-zeynep-tufekci.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/05/dr-zeynep-tufekci.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have two tickets available for Stuff You Missed in History Class Live in Seattle on the 13th. If you or someone you know wants ‘em, let me know.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Oct 2018 21:07:34 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/02/i-have-two.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/03/i-have-two.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;div style=&quot;position:relative; padding-bottom:62.50%&quot;&gt;&lt;iframe src=&quot;https://gfycat.com/ifr/SerpentineGrayAmurminnow&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100%&quot; style=&quot;position:absolute;top:0;left:0;&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;p&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://gfycat.com/gifs/detail/SerpentineGrayAmurminnow&quot;&gt;via Gfycat&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.reddit.com/r/baseball/comments/9kfdkh/watch_your_teams_playoff_odds_in_real_time_i/&quot;&gt;I animated FanGraphs’ projected playoff odds for the MLB each day of the season to commemorate the Mariners’ extraordinary failure.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m an Orioles &lt;em&gt;and&lt;/em&gt; Mariners fan. This hurts. Actually, the next few seasons are probably going to hurt. ⚾️&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 20:40:27 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/01/i-animated-fangraphs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/02/i-animated-fangraphs.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>20 Songs</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.blog/bradbarrish&quot;&gt;@bradbarrish&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;https://micro.whatevernevermind.com/2018/09/25/there-was-a.html&quot;&gt;linked a playlist of 20 songs&lt;/a&gt; that “truly represent [his] muscial point-of-view”. I loved the idea. It’s a vague prompt, and I’m interpreting it as 20 songs that shaped my musical taste. I’ve ordered these in roughly chronological order of &lt;em&gt;when I was introduced to the songs&lt;/em&gt;, not when they were released.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m also using this as an excuse to write up my memories of these songs, how I came to them, and what they meant to me. I wanted to pull this thread all the way through and add songs that are currently at the end of the threads these songs start, but the 20 song limitation wasn’t enough. That would be a fun follow-on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tl;dr:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/playlist/20-songs/pl.u-x5JlUMe3rM&quot;&gt;Apple Music Playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://open.spotify.com/user/jalvani/playlist/4pZ5osyZRKVpFcawXfO9CE?si=As2AnvY4QJu01rXCYnu6vQ&quot;&gt;Spotify Playlist&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Jim Croce - &lt;em&gt;Operator&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;My Dad’s musical taste was varied, but I think he only knew four or five artists’ names: Harry Belafonte, Randy Travis, Engelbert Humperdink, Neal Diamond, and Jim Croche. They all grated on me, except for Jim. &lt;em&gt;Bad, Bad Leroy Brown&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Time In a Bottle&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;I Got A Name&lt;/em&gt;. My favorite was the heartbreaking conversation Jim had with the operator when thinking of calling his ex. That’s still a resonant theme in music, some things don’t change. Simple guitar, a swelling refrain, and long car rides with my old man.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Beach Boys - &lt;em&gt;Sloop John B&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Mom gave me a cassette of the Beach Boys’ greatest hits when I was 3 or 4. I listened to it so much, I stretched the tape. I begged for a replacement, and stretched that one. Had to wait for a birthday to get another replacement. Sloop John B. and Wouldn’t It Be Nice were my favorites, but if I have to pick one, it’s an easy decision.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Beatles - &lt;em&gt;Eleanor Rigby&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Concept Beatles are the best Beatles, and the grimy English city life that Eleanor Rigby evoked just really did it for me. The feeling of indvidualsliving in shared lonlieness is so well captured, and the string backing is perfect.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Billy Joel - &lt;em&gt;Downeaster “Alexa”&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Storm Front was one of the first albums I asked my parents to buy me, after hearing the single We Didn’t Start the Fire. Downeaster Alexa was hurt.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Heart - &lt;em&gt;Barracuda&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I don’t have a specific memory of Barracuda, but I knew all the words as a kid, and it’s directly applicable to my love of Garbage, Amanda Palmer, Tori Amos, Pretty Girls Make Graves, etc. etc.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Amy Irving and Charles Fleischer - &lt;em&gt;Why Don’t You Do Right?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Like so many boys of my generation, I found Jessica Rabbit…eye opening. She turned me on to a lot of things, and one of them was smoky, sultry jazz singers.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pink Floyd - &lt;em&gt;Is Anybody Out There&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I heard this song entirely out of context sitting on the floor of the living room of my childhood home, idly listening to my dad’s massive box of mixtapes and tapes of songs he’d recorded from the radio (remember how satisfying it was to get a perfect recording where you started the tape at just the right moment and the DJ didn’t interrupt with some asinine commentary), and Syd Barrett’s asking for acknowledgement resonated so strongly in me. I had no idea who it was - Dad didn’t know - but six or eight years later I heard &lt;em&gt;The Wall&lt;/em&gt;, and everything made sense.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Ramones - &lt;em&gt;I Wanna Be Sedated&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Energetic beats paird with lyrics of not wanting to feel this constant energy hit close to home. That’s being a teenager.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;David Bowie - &lt;em&gt;Rock ‘n’ Roll Suicide&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;”Oh! No, love, you’re &lt;strong&gt;not&lt;/strong&gt; alone!” Chills. Every time.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;The Doors - &lt;em&gt;The End&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;There aren’t words for The End, so I won’t force them.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Del the Funky Homosapien - &lt;em&gt;If You Must&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Turned on by the Tony Hawk Pro Skater soundtrack, I couldn’t get enough of Del. When I heard Deltron 3030, it floored me. Hip Hop could be crerebral and funny and fun. It seems obvious now, but this was eye opening. (Pretty sure I remember it being “Del the Funkee Homosapien” and “If Ya Must” on the game, though)&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tori Amos - &lt;em&gt;Datura&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;A friend at summer camp let me borrow &lt;em&gt;Under the Pink&lt;/em&gt; overnight, and I listened to it in my bunk. I liked it, but she liked it more than I did, and that fact limited how close our friendship could be. &lt;em&gt;To Venus and Back&lt;/em&gt;, on the other hand, grabbed me immediately and hasn’t let go. It’s been nearly 20 years.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The Cure - &lt;em&gt;Just Like Heaven&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Depeche Mode - &lt;em&gt;Enjoy the Silence&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Nine Inch Nails - &lt;em&gt;Sanctified&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;New Order - &lt;em&gt;Age of Consent&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;These four, together, capture my teenage industrial/new-wave romanticism. &lt;em&gt;Age of Consent&lt;/em&gt; captured the feeling of seeing the fist light after partying all night in some black basement while listening to the other three. Which was pretty much how I spent my late teens and early 20s.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Bjork - &lt;em&gt;Human Behavior&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;Oh man, &lt;em&gt;Human Behavior&lt;/em&gt; opened my eyes. Before this, my only exposure to Bjork was &lt;em&gt;It’s Oh So Quiet&lt;/em&gt;, which is great but made me think she was a “Happy music” person. Obviously, I wasn’t paying attention.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Pixies - &lt;em&gt;Wave of Mutilation&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;I was tunred onto Pixies late, &lt;em&gt;Doolittle&lt;/em&gt; came out in ‘89, and I didn’t listen to it until I was in high school, probably a decade later. Didn’t matter. &lt;em&gt;Doolittle&lt;/em&gt; is timeless.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Tool - &lt;em&gt;Parabol/Parabola&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;This is a bit of a cheat, but the crescendo between the two tracks makes it. This specific transition led me into Godspeed! You Black Emperor and Mogwai. Between classes in college, I walked into one of Baltimore’s great local record shops (Record and Tape Traders, which was apparently and dissapointingly bought by FYE)  and asked the guy behind the counter if he could think of anything else that made me feel the way that transition did; like a wave crashing on me, like tension being released. He nailed it.
Also, this isn’t on the playlists because Tool is regressivly keeping their music off streaming services. Hope they come around.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;At The Drive-In - &lt;em&gt;One-Armed Scissor&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

    &lt;p&gt;In 1999, At the Drive-In was supposed to be the future of punk. &lt;em&gt;Relationship of Command&lt;/em&gt; was excellent, but the band dissolved, and Cedric and Omar moved on to the also-phenomenal The Mars Volta.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2018 11:25:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/10/01/songs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/10/01/songs.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Wallace Falls with a visiting friend and a 30# unstable pack #getoutside #dadface&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/e78b997449.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/dfe758335d.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/a89e87cd25.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/f3abffc0f9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;450&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/7e36579a0f.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 29 Sep 2018 11:22:50 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/09/29/wallace-falls-with.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/09/29/wallace-falls-with.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Siri Shortcuts and I love iCloud Photos, but putting the two together is a dance of crashes to the desktop, failures without error, and disappointment.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 25 Sep 2018 19:14:48 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/09/25/i-love-siri.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/09/26/i-love-siri.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;It makes me happy that Find My Friends is “Find Friends” on the homescreen. Maybe one day I will, iPhone. Maybe one day I will…&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 10 Sep 2018 16:55:35 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/09/10/it-makes-me.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/09/10/it-makes-me.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;A smoky day outside with friends is still a damn fine day. 
A recent #tbt to Tuesday on Mt. St. Helens with @jfuruno1, @jjfuruno, and @lindsay_alvani&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/d0fd0c4a74.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/a44beb4153.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/24b2adcbd7.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/dbb2320183.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/2764dc5e02.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;452&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/7837424e0b.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 23 Aug 2018 18:19:57 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/08/23/a-smoky-day.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/08/24/a-smoky-day.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Batman watering can, a hose, a four-year-old’s ingenuity, and sunshine #summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/9bbf10adf9.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 07 Aug 2018 18:44:28 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/08/07/batman-watering-can.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/08/08/batman-watering-can.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve crawled deep down a Fortnite rabbithole. The past 10 days have been dark. At least I still remember my kids’ names.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 31 Jul 2018 10:16:58 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/07/31/ive-called-deep.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/07/31/ive-called-deep.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aubrey the Uruk-hai #lookslikemeatsbackonthemenuboys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/51c5bb5410.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jul 2018 12:32:01 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/07/10/aubrey-the-urukhai.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/07/10/aubrey-the-urukhai.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/ab01d4b859.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sun, 08 Jul 2018 16:58:47 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/07/08/summer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/07/08/summer.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Made a friend while running errands this morning.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/f98356ff01.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;449&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 22 Jun 2018 14:22:08 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/06/22/made-a-friend.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/06/22/made-a-friend.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Summer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/fe20a348bc.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jun 2018 07:20:13 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/06/18/142013.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/06/18/142013.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Aubrey (2) found her nipples. She asked me what they’re called and I told her. “My sprinkles?” She said. So they’re sprinkles, now, and that’s my favorite thing.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 02 Jun 2018 08:18:08 -0700</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/06/02/aubrey-found-her.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/06/02/aubrey-found-her.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.espn.com/espn/feature/story/_/id/22624561/ichiro-suzuki-return-seattle-mariners-resolve-internal-battle&quot;&gt;This profile on Ichiro by Wright Thompson&lt;/a&gt; is beautiful and sad, and makes me so happy he’s a Mariner again.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 08 Mar 2018 08:53:18 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/03/08/this-profile-on.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/03/08/this-profile-on.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I had surgery to fix a lazy eye last week. Definitely felt sluggish on 18.1 today. I was realistically targeting 200, but secretly thought if everything clicked I could hit 256. I got 197. I’d like to say I left my ego at the door, but it still took a hit.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 24 Feb 2018 13:41:28 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/02/24/i-had-surgery.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/02/24/i-had-surgery.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Had an epiphany about Washingtonians this morning. They don’t feel temperature, but what they interpret as temperature is the presence or absence of sunlight. So 29°F and sunny is tee-shirt weather and 50°F and drizzling requires a puffy.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2018 09:23:40 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/02/19/had-an-epiphany.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/02/19/had-an-epiphany.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I just beat Kingdom: New Lands, and it’s the most fun I’ve had playing an iOS game in ages. It’s so well suited to touch, it’s impressive it was on PC first.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/kingdom-new-lands/id1118513354?mt=8&quot;&gt;itunes.apple.com/us/app/ki…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 13:40:55 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/02/03/i-just-beat.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/02/03/i-just-beat.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;According to Iain, I guess I have 203 toes?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/d196223332.jpg&quot; width=&quot;480&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2018 10:39:27 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/02/03/according-to-iain.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/02/03/according-to-iain.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Trouble’s coming&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/c5135071bf.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 30 Jan 2018 16:54:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/30/troubles-coming.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/31/troubles-coming.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Reducing my Fever</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been using &lt;a href=&quot;[feedafever.com](https://feedafever.com)&quot;&gt;Fever&lt;/a&gt; for nearly a decade; the site was launched in 2008, and I was an early adopter. I’ve waxed and waned my RSS reading, sometimes going through periods where Digg or Reddit or Twitter gave me more of my news, but over the past few years I’ve been back in Fever a lot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I didn’t know, but Fever’s creator and author, Shaun Inman, &lt;a href=&quot;[shauninman.com/archive/2...](https://shauninman.com/archive/2016/12/24/goodbye_mint_goodbye_fever)&quot;&gt;killed&lt;/a&gt; Fever and &lt;a href=&quot;[haveamint.com](http://haveamint.com/)&quot;&gt;Mint&lt;/a&gt; over a year ago in December 2016! It’s a testament to how well written this little PHP app is, and to self-hosting software, that my instances of Fever have been so reliable for so long. I’ve done almost no maintenance, occasionally clearing disk space on the server, but that’s it. It’s great. I only found out they were deprecated when I visited the site looking for information on using regex to filter specific posts from a couple of my feeds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’m looking for alternatives. I’m demoing &lt;a href=&quot;[feedbin.com](https://feedbin.com)&quot;&gt;Feedbin&lt;/a&gt; right now, and I like it so far. I do miss Fever’s clever aggregation feature&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, but I might be able to get something close by liberally applying auto-read actions, which actually very easily solved my needs I was using regex filters for in Fever. Good job, Feedbin!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Fever had this cool concept where some feeds could be marked as “Sparks”. They wouldn’t show up in your unread list, but they &lt;em&gt;would&lt;/em&gt; add to a “Hot” section. Feed items that used similar language or linked to the same URLs would be aggregated under “Hot”, with more popular terms and links getting a higher temperature, and thus being “hotter”. So clever, and super useful for especially for squeezing some benefit from the really high-volume feeds that I otherwise won’t read. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 12:00:16 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/23/reducing-my-fever.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/23/reducing-my-fever.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve spent a lot of today wondering what Dr. King would think of us, today. I suspect this look says it all. We’d do well to re-learn his lessons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/3588983423.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jan 2018 16:18:47 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/15/ive-spent-a.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/16/ive-spent-a.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Got OpenGarage.io + HomeBridge working, tonight. Honestly, I love this home automation stuff. It’s so fun.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jan 2018 23:17:40 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/11/got-opengarageio-homebridge.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/12/got-opengarageio-homebridge.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Body Measurement</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been lax in keeping track of my quantifiable health data since I moved from Baltimore. I’ve never been a big fan of having a scale at home since I can get obsessive over checking my weight which can lead to unhealthy decisions. Using the scale only weekly and at the gym was a big part of how I got into shape.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But, my Crossfit gym doesn’t have a scale, and I’ve been interested in capturing details more than just my weight, so I cracked and bought a Nokia Health (formerly Withings) &lt;a href=&quot;[www.amazon.com/dp/B071DV...](http://www.amazon.com/dp/B071DV5N9X/?tag=jalvani-20)&quot;&gt;Body Cardio&lt;/a&gt;&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. I was apprehensive before buying, but &lt;strong&gt;my verdict after a few weeks is that it’s exactly what I want in a scale&lt;/strong&gt; by being much more than scales have been in the past.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s a quick summary of my favorite things about it:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Is wifi&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, not bluetooth, so it directly sends data to your profile on Nokia’s health webapp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Tracks weight, body composition (lean muscle mass, fat mass, body water weight, bone mass), BMI&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;, heartrate, and &lt;a href=&quot;[en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Puls...](https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Pulse_wave_velocity)&quot;&gt;Pulse wave velocity&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;em&gt;Does the above while differentiating between individuals in a household&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I have a profile, and so does Lindsay. My son climbs on the scale just about every day, but just to play. His measurements just get collected in a “no profile” bucket, and I clear them out every few days.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like many, I’ve been focusing on dropping fat after the holidays, and I’ve done exactly that, averaging a pound and a half loss since mid-December. I think a lot of that is thanks to the accountability provided by having these measurements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I did run into an issue where the app and documentation said that an account wasn’t needed to get the scale on my wireless network. I figured it’d have me create an account later in the process. It didn’t, and when I called support, the rep had me create an account, and go through the process again, and it worked just fine. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt; &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;sup&gt;2&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;Setting aside arguments about the value of BMI, it’s a metric that’s interesting if you’re tracking other metrics and don’t get too hung up on it. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2018 08:45:19 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/08/body-measurement.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/08/body-measurement.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Iain (3) has Incredible Hulk underwear, but doesn’t really know who Hulk is. Calls him “The Credible Puck”, which seems like the basis for a fun rewrite of A Midsummer Night’s Dream.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jan 2018 19:55:11 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/05/iain-has-incredible.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/06/iain-has-incredible.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Questions about Zone v. Calorie Counting</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been reading about the Zone diet, recently. I&amp;#8217;m coming at this as a long-time calorie and macro counter. I&amp;#8217;m left with a few questions, and thought it might be interesting to document my thoughts. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I’ll preface this discussion with the fact that I’m certainly not a nutritionist. I’m a fitness enthusiast who had my share of weight issues which stemmed from being a really active kid and teen who didn’t know &lt;em&gt;how&lt;/em&gt; to eat. As a result, when I got to college and wasn’t as active in my sport, I gained a ton of weight. Over the years, I learned about fitness and nutrition, and I’ve gotten pretty good at manipulating both to achieve my goals. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was going to start with a quick summary of zone, but to really understand this, I think we need to go back a step.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calories&quot;&gt;Calories&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I said, I’m a longtime macro-counter. The three &amp;#8220;macro&amp;#8221; nutrients are proteins, carbohydrates, and fats. There are others: fibers, acids, etc., but these three are relevant to this discussion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They break down something &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Food_energy#Nutrition_labels&quot;&gt;like this&lt;/a&gt;: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;colgroup&gt;
&lt;col style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;col style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/colgroup&gt;

&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;Nutrient&lt;/th&gt;
	&lt;th style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;cal/g&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;Fat&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;9&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;Proteins&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;Carbs&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;4&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Ethanol&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
	&lt;td style=&quot;text-align:left;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;7&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The list isn&amp;#8217;t comprehensive; I specifically included the macros we&amp;#8217;re discussing, and I intentionally left Ethanol (Drinking Alcohol) in the list. I&amp;#8217;ll circle back to that later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This list is based on pure protein, fat, and carbohydrates. In actuality, foods we eat are all combinations of the above. For example, ground beef is a mix of protein and fat, and is usually expressed as a percentage or ratio - eg. 80% lean, or 80/20 (where 80% is lean protein and 20% is fat). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;summaryofzone&quot;&gt;Summary of Zone&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Most of this, I&amp;#8217;ve pulled from &lt;a href=&quot;http://library.crossfit.com/free/pdf/cfjissue21_May04.pdf&quot;&gt;Issue 21 of the CrossFit Journal&lt;/a&gt; from May 2004.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zone diet is based on macro counting but applies an abstraction layer in the form of &amp;#8220;Blocks&amp;#8221;. One block is 7g of protein, 9 grams of carbohydrates, or 3g of fat&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:15392&quot; id=&quot;fnref:15392&quot; title=&quot;see footnote&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;[1]&lt;/a&gt;. A meal contains &lt;code&gt;N&lt;/code&gt; blocks of protein, fat, and carbohydrates, so a 1-block meal would have one block of each, and works out to about 90 calories&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:32199&quot; id=&quot;fnref:32199&quot; title=&quot;see footnote&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;[2]&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Zone diet consumption is metered by applying a number of blocks to daily meals, with three meals and two snacks per day. Someone who is a &amp;#8220;Four Blocker&amp;#8221; has meals that are four blocks in size, or about 360 cal. Snacks, similarly, are a number of blocks from 1&amp;#8211;4+. The number of blocks per meal is roughly determined by an individual&amp;#8217;s sex and size. &lt;em&gt;Thus, Zone is really a framework for determining portion size and ensuring a balanced diet.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journal helpfully provides a list of foods that comprise one block of each macro. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;calorieandmacrocounting&quot;&gt;Calorie and Macro Counting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Calorie counters usually start from a calculation of their Total Daily Energy Expenditure (TDEE), which is a combination of their Basal Metabolic Rate (BMR) and average caloric burn. BMR is the base number of calories a person needs to maintain weight without exercise. Adding average additional caloric load - which can come from an active commute, a physical job, or good old exercise - gives TDEE. There are a lot of calculators for estimating TDEE, and it’s easy to rathole on which is best for what purposes. I’m not getting into that here. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Consuming fewer calories than your TDEE is consuming a deficit of calories, and leads to weight loss. Consuming more than your TDEE is a surplus, and leads to weight gain. Simple. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In general, the guidance is .8&amp;#8211;1.2g of protein per pound of bodyweight. This amount of protein is good for growing and maintaining muscle mass, and leads to a feeling of satiation. Apart from that, though, I never found good guidance about splits of fats and carbs. When I was most successful, I was eating about 20% of my daily intake as carbs, 40% from protein, and 40% from fat. It took some experimentation to figure that out, but I made small adjustments to my diet over a period of years. I’ll also say that I’ve never been working out 5&amp;#8211;6 days each week, but 3&amp;#8211;4 is pretty typical, and has been for years. Nutritional needs are likely different with that degree or exertion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Both in Zone and counting, there’s an element of tracking your consumption, and ensuring the portions being tracked are accurate. That takes dedication either way. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;bulksandcuts&quot;&gt;Bulks and Cuts&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With macro counting, there’s also a concept of bulks and cuts. It’s difficult to gain strength (adding lean muscle) in a caloric deficit, and it’s virtually impossible to lose fat at a caloric surplus. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To lose about a pound per week, your consumption should be about 500 cal below TDEE. 500 calories above TDEE will gain you about a pound per week. Couple this with strength training, and smart application of cardio, and you can add muscle mass and lose fat very effectively.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;questions&quot;&gt;Questions&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This sets up my questions. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;In Zone, it seems like there’s no concept of bulks and cuts. Do I understand that correctly? If I do, why no bulks and cuts?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If there are bulks and cuts, would I go to a “heavy gain” (5 block meals, 4 block snacks) for a bulk, and a more moderate 5 block meal/3 block snack or 4/4 for a cut?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I adjust for exercise? While macro counting, I add calories burned in exercise to my TDEE, and scale my percentage of macros accordingly. That doesn’t seem to be the case with Zone, or it’s not addressed.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How do you handle non-workout days with zone? It seems to assume a CrossFit “ideal” of 5&amp;#8211;6 days per week of strenuous exercise.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;whereilanded&quot;&gt;Where I landed&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I see a lot of smarts in Zone, but the value is in the framework, not the application. I disagree with the splits of macros that Zone applies. Keeping carbs low over a period of time teaches your body to break down fat for fuel, which is super valuable&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:49006&quot; id=&quot;fnref:49006&quot; title=&quot;see footnote&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;[3]&lt;/a&gt;. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I know that my TDEE is currently pretty close to 2300 cal. I shoot for 1800 cal while cutting, and 2500 while bulking. I’ll likely take this as a motivator to rethink my percentages and how I bulk. In the past, I scaled protein and filled in with whatever. Once I hit my macros for the day, it was on. I could eat whatever to make up the last calories. Now I’ll try to maintain my splits more consistently. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;alcohol&quot;&gt;Alcohol&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I promised to come back to booze, didn’t I? The 7cal/gram of ethanol does help explain why so many people say they really got traction once they dramatically reduced alcohol consumption. It’s worth keeping in mind that %ABV is the method of determining how much ethanol is in a drink, and a drink has other nutrients as well. Beer, for example, has a both alcohol sugars, and complex carbohydrates. A 5 ounce pour of wine is approximately 150g. Far from scientific, but opening my wine cabinet and pulling out a red, it’s 13.9% ABV. Let’s do some quick math: &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;14% (Rounded 13.9% up) of 150g is 21g&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;21g at 7 cal/g is 147 cal per glass of wine, plus residual sugars&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Booze trips up your splits no matter what. Now, I’m a big fan of moderation. Moderation in everything, including moderation.Just be conscious of the impact these things have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn:15392&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There&amp;#8217;s an assumption that any 7g of protein will itself contain 1.5 g of fat, so a block contains only 1.5 &lt;em&gt;additional&lt;/em&gt; grams of fat.  &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:15392&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#160;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn:32199&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Protein: 7g * 4cal = 28cal of protein, Carbs: 9g * 4 = 36, Fat: 3g * 9cal = 27cal&lt;br /&gt;
28+36+28=91 cal &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:32199&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#160;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li id=&quot;fn:49006&quot;&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I don’t know much about it, but I can’t see how this approach would be good for younger athletes. Brain development requires loads of carbs and fat. Quick searches didn’t lead to any good studies to read, but that doesn’t meant they haven’t been done. I just don’t know of them.  &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:49006&quot; title=&quot;return to article&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#160;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 02 Jan 2018 17:27:06 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2018/01/02/questions-about-zone.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2018/01/03/questions-about-zone.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Morning view&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2018/293bb30f66.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;313&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Mon, 11 Dec 2017 08:05:17 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/12/11/morning-view.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/12/11/morning-view.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Overcooked the eggs, but man that’s a good looking bowl.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2017/2981ed0f7e.jpg&quot; width=&quot;599&quot; height=&quot;600&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 05 Dec 2017 18:16:02 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/12/05/overcooked-the-eggs.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/12/06/overcooked-the-eggs.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;WhiteFox True Fox Keyboard &lt;a href=&quot;http://jehanalvani.com/blog/2017/12/1/whitefox-true-fox-keyboard&quot;&gt;jehanalvani.com&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;http://micro.jehanalvani.com/uploads/2017/9aa3962725.jpg&quot; width=&quot;600&quot; height=&quot;302&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 01 Dec 2017 16:50:41 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/12/01/whitefox-true-fox.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/12/02/whitefox-true-fox.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;One more:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/PxQvW7NNmno&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 14:04:58 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/11/29/one-more.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/11/29/one-more.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;And, since I can’t help myself when it comes to Jim Henson, here’s the old (strangely violent) Wilkins Coffee ads he did, featuring early muppets:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/HVewx3-9x24&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 14:04:50 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/11/29/and-since-i.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/11/29/and-since-i.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <title>Jim Henson's Bizarre Anti-Paperwork Ad for IBM</title>
        
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Adafruit posted this &lt;a href=&quot;[blog.adafruit.com/2017/11/2...](https://blog.adafruit.com/2017/11/27/jim-henson-wanted-to-free-us-from-paperwork/)&quot;&gt;on their blog&lt;/a&gt; today, and I’d never seen it before. From the Jim Henson Company’s &lt;a href=&quot;[www.youtube.com/watch](https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=_IZw2CoYztk)&quot;&gt;YouTube channel&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;In 1967, Henson was contracted by IBM to make a film extolling the virtues of their new technology, the MT/ST, a primitive word processor. The film would explore how the MT/ST would help control the massive amount of documents generated by a typical business office. Paperwork Explosion, produced in October 1967, is a quick-cut montage of images and words illustrating the intensity and pace of modern business. Henson collaborated with Raymond Scott on the electronic sound track.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;560&quot; height=&quot;315&quot; src=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_IZw2CoYztk&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Wed, 29 Nov 2017 13:54:25 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/11/29/jim-hensons-bizarre.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/11/29/jim-hensons-bizarre.html</guid>
      </item>
    
      <item>
      	
        <description>&lt;p&gt;🛫&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Tue, 28 Nov 2017 14:36:15 -0800</pubDate>
        <link>https://micro.jehanalvani.com/2017/11/28/223615.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://jalvani.micro.blog/2017/11/28/223615.html</guid>
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
